MARTIN COSTELLO

1 Argent Way, Bradford, BD4 0LW 07554 045975; martincostello1959@gmail.com Target Role; Construction Site Manager Full UK Driving Licence

SUMMARY

Motivated, focused and high achieving construction industry professional with a proven track record of coordinating, leading and overseeing teams on a multitude of projects. Offering excellent all-round leadership and client facing qualities having managed project delivery and large-scale teams, Goal oriented, driven and safety-oriented person that takes great pride in his work by engaging with the workforce, resolving issues and pre-empting challenges. Able to guide various teams simultaneously with an aptitude for preparing work scopes and leading projects on new builds, renovations and shop fit-outs. With more than 20 years' experience he is open to ideas on opportunities as a Site Manager. Will add value immediately to any employer.

KEY SKILLS & STRENGTHS

CSCS Gold Card; SMSTS; Site Safety Inductions; Labour Supervision; Planning Manpower; Staff Management Tracking Site Progress; Health & Safety Trained; Attending Site Meetings; Supplier Liaison; Safety Inspections Ordering Site Materials; Attending Meetings; Construction Best Practice; Groundwork Activities; Quality Control Managing Site Teams; Enforcing High Standards; Safety Best Practice; Project Handover; Technical Drawings

CAREER HISTORY

SELF EMPLOYED 1994 - PRESENT

Various Projects; Site Manager/Joiner/Foreman/Site Agent/Kitchen & Bedroom Fitter
Etap Hotel Construction, 2007; Eccleshill Health Centre, Site Agent; Bradford University's Malik Halls of
Residence, Site Manager for 5 Years; Malik Halls £3M Project; Galliford £1.5M Project; City Hotel in Leeds £3M
Refurbishment; Waites Premier Build Contracts Varied from £500K to £10M

MAIN PROJECTS & HIGHLIGHTS;

- Finishing Manager, Urban Splash Homes, on dwellings ranging from £250K to £1M in Manchester
- Royal Horticultural Society; £36M project on a restoration job in Manchester which will be the biggest garden in Europe when completed in 2020
- Primark Sep 2017 Mar 2018; Managed a £500K project in Blackpool rebuilding and refitting steels to parapet wall; Supervised the erection of 8 lifts x 71 metres of scaffold, then the demolition of a 71m x 2m parapet wall; Reinstated marine steel ledgers and rebuilt a new parapet wall with features
- Managing manpower and trades on high end retail park shop fit-outs at McArthur Glenn Outlets nationwide for Estee Lauder, The Body Shop, McDonalds, Marks & Spencer and Asda
- 7 Formation Ltd, New Ellington Hotel Leeds; Set up the site and marked out new rooms / new drainage
 KEY RESPONSIBILITIES;
 - Enforcing health and safety across site operations as the link with clients, suppliers and tradesman
 - · Collaborating with suppliers to order materials and checking quantities of materials when delivered
 - · Overseeing the workforce for safety, site conduct and reviewing the building plans and site drawings
 - · Working to high specifications and adapting to changes in project focus, designs and timescales
 - Dealing with various architects, labour, trades & contractors to focus on shared goals and objectives
 - Maintaining quality delivery by performing checks on workmanship, progress and on-site productivity
 - Providing direction to teams of staff when faced with tight schedules and specific budget parameters
 - Extensive experience in all aspects of on-site joinery, fitting and installation work and construction
 - Organising inductions for health and safety briefs, running tool box talks and ordering materials
 - · Supervising all trades, joiners, mechanical electrics, plumbing, ground works and the induction of staff
 - Coordinating staff time shifts to ensure manpower and chairing team briefings regarding updates
 - Providing daily reports of activity to detail progress, cost tracking, features and any site challenges
 - Attending meetings regarding projects and liaising with architects, all tradesman and sub-contractors
 - · Making client changes and implementing recommendations to achieve the features and customisation
 - · Undertaking work inspections and setting clear accountabilities for productivity and project delivery
 - Signing off completed work to ensure compliance with quality control regulations and specifications

MARTIN COSTELLO

1 Argent Way, Bradford, BD4 0LW 07554 045975; martincostello1959@gmail.com Target Role; Construction Site Manager Full UK Driving Licence

EARLY CAREER

PBH Shop Fitters, Building Bars & Counters, 1990 - 1994
FD Kitchens, Manchester, Fitting Bespoke Kitchens (Became Foreman Fitter), 1986 - 1990
British Army 2nd Battalion Parachute Regiment/Sniper Platoon (Served in the Falkland's in 1982, Northern Ireland 1983, Belize 1984), 1981 - 1985

Travelled to Thailand to Study and Fight Muay Thai Boxing (Won 21 Fights in Bangkok Stadium). 1980 - 1981 Schreiber Furniture, Woodworking Apprenticeship, 1976 - 1980

QUALIFICATIONS & TRAINING

2018 Chartered Institute of Builders Level 4 Construction Management Certificate
Hold the CSCS Gold Card (and shortly applying for the CSCS Black Card)
2018 Fire Marshall; 2018 Asbestos Awareness; 2016 SMSTS
2015 - 2018 Bradford College, CSCS Site Supervisor
2014 - 2014 Milton Keynes College, City & Guilds Level 1 in Plumbing
2014 - 2014 Milton Keynes College, National Chartered Institute of Environmental Health Level 2 in Health & Safety at Work

2013 - 2013 Milton Keynes College, Emergency First Aid at Work Level 2
2011 - 2012 Manchester College, City & Guilds Diploma Level 2 in Floor & Wall Tiling
2011 - 2012 Manchester College, City & Guilds Diploma Level 2 in Bricklaying
2011 - 2013 Manchester College, Level 1 & 2 in Adult Literacy
2011 - 2013 Manchester College, Level 1 & 2 in Functional Skills Numeracy
2011 - 2013 Milton Keynes College, ITQ Level 1 & 2 in IT - CLAIT International Award
2010 - 2010 Manchester College, BSC Level 1 Award in Health & Safety at Work
2010 - 2010 Bradford College, NCFE Award Business Development and Enterprise
2009 - 2010 Bradford College, BTEC National Award Level 3 in Construction Management
(Passed with 5 Distinctions and 1 Merit)

2008 - 2009 Bradford College, City & Guilds Level 1 in Mathematics and English Language 1976 - 1979 Manchester College, City & Guilds Wood Machining & Furniture Craft 1971 - 1976 Newall Green High, GCE 'O' Levels; English Literature, English Language, Maths, Woodwork

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Thai Boxing; Mixed Martial Arts; Swimming; Keeping Fit

REFERENCES

AVAILABLE ON REQUEST